

CRISTIAN **CARTOG**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER / TECHNICAL LEAD

+40 744 423 988 cristiancartog@gmail.com Sibiu, Romania

SKILLS

Java, Javascript, Typescript

Back-End: Spring Framework (Core, Boot, Data, Security, Web), EJB 3.1, JaxRs, JPA

Front-End: Angular 5, Angular 1, JQuery, CSS, HTML

DB: Mongo, Oracle, Exasol, MySql, Elasticsearch

Jira, Confluence, Jenkins

Git, SVN

Nomad, Docker

Maven, Gradle, Npm, Ant

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Expert, Java EE 6 Persistence API Developer (2013)

Sun Certified Developer for Java Web Services 5 (2010)

Sun Certified Web Component Developer for J2EE 5 (2009)

Sun Certified Java Programmer for Java 6 (2009)

Cisco Certified Network Associate (2009)

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN
AUTOMATION AND
COMPUTER SCIENCE
"POLITEHNICA" UNIVERSITY
OF TIMISOARA
2009

ABOUT ME

I am a consultant / contractor / freelancer with **14 years** of experience, **only** interested in remote work.

I help companies around the world implement maintainable, scalable and efficient distributed systems.

Let's connect and discuss how I can help your business!

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / TECHNICAL LEAD

WINDELN.DE | SIBIU MAY 2016 - PRESENT

The company uses it's own PIM system which has a few issues: badly implemented, unscalable, untested, generated lots of data issues and was hard to maintain. A new PIM implementation was needed.

- increased the product processing speed by 120% by eliminating unnecessary conversions and migrating it to the newer versions of mongo and Elasticsearch.
- increased product validation throughput by 600% by rewriting the validation logic, moving it in a separate service and deploying it on multiple machines
- reduced the indexing process from 4h to 10 min by creating a new reindexing service
- reduced the technical debt by 95% (according to SonarQube) and lead a team of 5 developers.

Skills used: Java, Spring Boot, activemq, rabbitmq, javascript, typescript, groovy, angular, Junit, mockito, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, maven, jenkins, nomad, git.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / TECHNICAL LEAD

ROPARDO | SIBIU AUG 2014 - APR 2016

JRA (Job Role Advisor): The company needed an application that would allow managers to set possible career paths and job roles to employees based on their skill sets.

- reduced decision maker's time by 50% by implementing batch processes that would automatically do employee-to-job role assignments
- implemented 20% of the UI and core services and utilities
- overall the application would save 80% of the managers' time spent on employee skill evaluation. The company has around 350.000 employees.

Skills used: Java 7, EJB 3.1, JaxRs, Javascript, Dojo 8, WebSphere, mybatis, DB2, ant, IBM "Rational" tool suite

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

MINDMATICS | SIBIU MAY 2012 - SEP 2014

MCC (Mopay Configuration Center): The client wanted all company office processes (user management, contract definitions, banking data management, package filtering, etc) to be done through one unified interface: a web application that would simulate a desktop environment (multiple windows, taskbar, start menu, control panel and notifications).

- reduced back-end latency by 50% through improved ORM mappings and better JPA queries.
- implemented 50% of the features and 70% of the core services and utilities
- reduced the application load time by 80% through a build configuration that generated a compressed, minified and obfuscated UI artifact.

Skills used: Java 6, Spring 3 (core, mvc, security), JPA (with Hibernate), SQL, oracle DB, tomcat 7, ExtJs 4.2, HTML, CSS3, junit, gradle, SVN, jenkins.